and we have ICICI Lombard on our list
right now as we were talking about you
know the general insurance and the life
insurance space we decided to invite the
management to speak about uh the growth
that they've seen the company is
actually clocked in a very strong gross
direct premium income growth of 17 but
the profit growth was quite muted in
terms of different segments it was
Health which contributed most of the
growth while motor remained weak this
time around we have gopal balachandra
the Chief Financial Officer and the
chief risk officer at icsl Lombard
General Insurance who joins in I'm Mr
balachandran uh good morning and
greetings of the season to you your
entire team at icsl ombud I wanted to
ask you about the private cast segment
because that has seen some weakness this
time and you also mentioned in your
conference call that there is some
pricing pressure that you're seeing in
this uh in this part of the market uh
can you tell us what is the outlook here
on and how much could the growth be over
the next fiscal or so
yeah so good morning Sonia uh seasons
greetings to you and to all all of those
at CNBC and obviously to all your
viewers as well uh you've been Advanced
wishes and a very happy question in
terms of uh how does one see let's say
growth playing out particularly let's
say on the motor side uh I think the
good part is I think uh relative to the
last couple of years where obviously we
had seen slow down in new vehicle sales
that seems to be kind of coming up
reasonably well particularly on the
segment that you referred to on the
private car I think definitely the
demand momentum I'm sure when you get to
hear also on the channel from most of
the oems I think the event seems to be
quite uh solid
um I think the challenge what
essentially happens is more from a
pricing uh competitiveness standpoint
and you're right I think at this point
of time at an industry level
particularly in the private car side the
pricing is far more aggressive and just
some if I were to just kind of put a
data point while we may not have
industry splits across Private Car two
wheeler and commercial vehicles but if
you look at the overall mode motor
combined ratios for the industry as a
whole in quarter one that number was
about 124 combined ratio this is both
loss ratios Plus cost of doing business
now that's obviously at a significant
elevated levels and therefore given the
elevated levels of pricing that is
sustaining in the market from an Isis
loan board standpoint I think in line
with what we have normally been doing we
are a bit cautious and that's the reason
you would have seen our overall motor
growth let's say uh at close to about 14
for this half year whereas the industry
growth would have been close to bullets
18 19 but that's generally
selecting risks whenever we see
significant elevated levels of price
aggression we obviously stay invested in
the distribution franchise but obviously
in stock so far as risk selection is
concerned we tend to get a bit cautious
there on right gopal hi good morning uh
so just to briefly on the
passenger vehicle side uh you know one
believes that you've given up some
market share uh could could you uh
confirm that can you tell us where
you're at I'm talking about uh premium
income and uh I think on the commercial
vehicle front you've gained market share
where you where are you at and what are
your aspirations both go on
absolutely I think Prashant your point
is right I think which is what I kind of
mentioned I think uh when I when I gave
the aggregate motor numbers uh our
growth in the half year was about as I
said 14 the industry growth would have
been close to about 18 19 uh so to that
direction obviously we would not have uh
we would have underperformed in so far
as overall motor is concerned and within
that particularly on the private car
segment I think we we have got a far
more cautious insofar as this selection
is concerned and hence to that extent uh
we would have kind of possibly let go
some market share in that particular
segment however in some of the other
portfolios when it comes to two wheelers
and commercial vehicles we generally get
to see a lot of positive ability to
reselect portfolios and particularly on
the commercial vehicles segment what we
have been speaking through is to get to
a mix which in the past has been at
about close to about 17 18 of our
overall motor revenues have been
commercial vehicles we had said we would
like to see that mix going closer to
about 24 25 and not necessarily get up
to the industry of 45 percent which is
the industry mix for Series so hence if
you would have looked at our field
numbers our overall commercial vehicle
makes contribution has been close to 23
24 the growth in that segment for the
half year has been almost close to about
56 percent uh private care would have
been more or less flat uh two wheeler we
would have kind of grown at almost about
17-18 all right hi gopal morning uh you
know your first Hub gdpi that's a
Crosstrek premium income that's around
23 percent how sustainable is this
what's the outlook for f523 if you could
try to give us a sense out there and you
mentioned a couple of times about the
combined ratio that's around 105 what's
the outlook on that front as well as the
loss ratio well for the first half it's
improved so on a sequential basis it's
gone up a little bit for the year though
what do you see the loss ratio
stabilizing at growth I want a combined
ratio as well as loss Outlook go ahead
yeah so I think uh so if you look at uh
uh we're kind of when you have when we
look at it from Isis number standpoint
both for quarter one and Quarter Two we
have actually outperformed the market uh
in q1 the industry was roughly about 20
to 23 I think we are at about 24 25
uh and if you look at uh on Quarter Two
the industry growth was about ten
percent uh we were at about 17 uh so
overall for the half year we are about
23 the point that you made industry
growth was roughly about 15 uh in terms
of aggregate revenues uh we are quite
excited with the growth prospect that we
take to see in each of the preferred
segments that we can generally State
invested in whether it is motor whether
it is health or for the matter of fact
even the commercial lines I think we are
extremely positive on on each of those I
think we believe there is a sustained
momentum in terms of growth let me pick
up each of those segments uh health for
example what we have been talking
through is significantly stay invested
in expanding distribution particularly
on the retail Health franchise and quite
happy to note that for the month of
September our growth rates which is at
about 21 percent is even faster than the
Standalone Health companies and that's
typically the kind of Benchmark that you
would like to largely work with and
that's an area where we are kind of
significantly investing in expanding
distribution our product expansion is
also something where we haven't done
investing a lot of the ideal take care
app that's doing well and hence overall
health momentum is positive and
therefore the growth is likely to kind
of sustain aspirate into second half uh
to a second point on combined ratios I
think at this point of time we are at
maybe at close to 105 there about what
we had indicated is for the next couple
of years which is for the current year
and the next year we should see the
combined ratios because we are investing
in expanding distribution and franchise
the compound issues are likely to stay
around 104 or thereabout post which we
should see a declining Trend or of the
combined ratio trajectory okay on the
last part of the health ratio's front I
think uh it's purely a function of the
way we Select Portfolio
we believe it could vary up across
different segments but broadly it will
stay within that range of
sorry briefly just running out of time
so want to squeeze in as much as
possible I think you've indicated on the
retail Health front you will take you
will assess if you need to take price
increases uh I think the last price
increase was in the third quarter of 21.
uh have you done that are you going to
do it
so at this point of time we continue to
assess the portfolio experience Prashant
and that's something that we uh every on
a quarter on quarter basis at this point
of time I think the what we are getting
to see is definitely there is increased
levels of claim inflation on the health
front almost a high ticket claim
inflation is what we are saying and
therefore we are watching the
development of how the overall fully
loss experiences are playing out and if
we will take a pricing okay since we're
talking about pricing on the regulatory
front there's also this bhima sugam
Insurance Exchange that's coming through
right will that affect pricing in any
way will it make it more competitive uh
will there be more penetration how do
you think things will change
so Sonia if you look at I think
fundamentally the thought process from a
regulatory standpoint is to
significantly embark on increasing
penetration and therefore I think
whatever the regulator is doing they are
creating all enabling environments for
us to be able to do that and clearly
biva sutam will be one of those uh
channels of offering which will make it
viable more from a customer standpoint
to your point on competitive intensity I
think General Insurance is a sector has
generally been relatively competitive
and therefore that's likely to continue
I think it's a question of staying
focused over a long term in terms of
risk which portfolio selection you want
to underwrite yes and corresponding will
it put pressure on pricing overall do
you think simple will it will it I think
yeah
I think overall in general irrespective
whether bhima super otherwise okay this
particular has generally been
competitive I think it's a question of
the company's ability to stay focused on
underwriting risks all right and stay
disciplined on bottom line okay I think
I'm sorry if we pushed you a little bit
there it's based on time so what are to
get as much thank you very much for
joining us so gopal it's a pleasure as
all